## Robert Bailey

Gameplay Programmer and Level Designer Portfolio: http://thrownerror.github.io

Email: emailrobertb@gmail.com Phone: (843) 364-1732

http://www.linkedin.com/in/robBaileyGD

## **Projects**

 ColorCoded: Color-based logic puzzle game made in Unity. Focused on puzzle development, microtransaction implementation, new player experience, and mobile porting. Closed Alpha currently on Google Play and iOS stores.

Awards: Imagine Cup 2017 Semifinalist, Received MAGIC @ RIT Co-Up 2017 Funding Best UI Winner: RPI Gamesfest 2017

- VRoom Project: Unreal Engine VR car combat game developed with an eight peson team for the Vive. Focused on combining arcade controls with VR immersion. Worked as producer and game design lead. Hosted on itch.io.
- Swingy Dinghy: Global Game Jam (2017) Unity project. Zen game for 1-2 players. Worked on clouds and collectible integration, as well as gameplay polish and feel. Hosted on itch.io.
- Killing Floor 2 Arena: Survival map for Tripwire's "Killing Floor 2," themed around an abandoned sports arena. Developed in the UDK editor over 8 weeks. Hosted on Steam workshop.

## **Skills**

Programming: C# (5 yrs), C++ (3 yrs), Javascript (4 yrs)

**Software:** Unity 5.2.0-2017.2.1, Photoshop 2016-17, Visual Studios 2015-17, Unreal Engine 4.14, UDK (and XCOM/KF2 variants), InDesign 2017, Maya 2016

Hardware: HTC Vive, iPad, Android phones

Tools: Unity Services, SourceTree, Gitlab, FileZilla,

Microsoft Excel

## Experience

# MAGIC Spell Studios, LLC Developer May 2017-Aug 2017

Worked on development and refinment of ColorCoded full-time under MAGIC Spell Studios @ RIT

- Received and incorporated feedback and critique from industry professionals
- Focused on implementation of over 100 additional levels, visual polish passes, porting to new platforms, usability, and improving player satisfaction
- Hosted public playtesting, developed iterative practices and mobile standards. Ended with closed Alpha release

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester NY IGM Teaching Assistant Aug 2016- Present Level Design, Data Structures and Algorithms

- Playtest, analyze, critique, and assiste with projects using a variety of games, tools, engines, and platforms
- Work to help students learn fundamentals of C++, including point usage and memory management.
- Tutor students, develop project rubrics and grade student work under supervision of IGM professors
- Provide feedback and critique across various genres and styles of games, including RTS, FPS, and Platformers

#### IGM Lab Tech Worker Jan 2018-Present

- Assist students in subjects across the IGM curriculum.
- Work to address technical and hardware problems in labs and classrooms.

### Resident Assistant Aug 2015-May 2017

- Worked with supervisors and staff to create a safe and welcoming community environment in dormitories
- Designed engaging floor events, mediated interpersonal conflicts, and reported regularly to supervisor
- Independently mediated conflicts across dorm life
- Developed communication and teamwork skills, and worked across ASL language barriers in residents and staff

## Education

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester NY Bachelor/Master of Science dual degree in Game Design and Development. Est. Grad: May 2019 GPA: 3.97, Member of Honors college at RIT 2014-Present

## **Activities**

Volunteer moderator of Humans vs Zombies, a 300+ player weeklong outside game (2014-Present) Interactive Games and Media volunteer ambassador (2016-Present)
Rochester Wargamer Association and Guild Rudicon volunteer (2015-16)
Certified SCUBA Diver